这就回厨房了? 快把菜放下
Straight back to the kitchen? Just leave the vegetables.
这样不行，去休息吧
This won't do. Go take some rest.
我该怎么办？
What do I do?
如果我不进厨房，这里就不像是家
Till I don't enter the kitchen, it doesn't feel like home.
过来炒菜，我马上回来
Watch this, I'll be back.
1000卢比
It's 1000 rupees.
哈尔沙德一定有计划，对吧? 很快就会解决的
Harshad Bhai is planning something, right? It will all work out soon.
我要去斯里兰卡找份工作
I'm getting a job... in Sri Lanka.
直接去斯里兰卡？
All the way to Sri Lanka?
我总不能在家里无所事事吧？
I can't keep sitting idle at home, can I?
你在外面打工那么努力... 还要做所有的家务事..
You work so hard at the parlour... and then all the household chores...
你说完了吗？
Are you done?
打工赚的钱足够经营这个家了，对吧？
The parlour is paying enough to run the house, right?
我喜欢在那里工作
And I like working there.
他们下个月要给我涨工资
They're increasing my salary next month.
听我说
Listen to me.
你不是还跟哈尔沙德说
Weren't you the one telling Harshad Bhai...
时间能治愈一切？
...that time is a great healer?
所以，给时间个机会
So then, time needs some time.
只要两分钟，爸爸晚餐很快好了
Just two minutes, Pappa. Dinner is almost ready.
我们还欠苏雷什 · 巴海多少钱？
How much do we still owe Suresh Bhai?
损失了一百万卢比
It's a loss of 10 lakhs.
我们还了三千七百万卢比
We've returned three, seven lakhs are pending.
当一个人在家里有了金子..
When one has gold at home...
才能睡得安稳
...one sleeps peacefully.
你认为我们的长辈为什么积累黄金？
Why do you think our elders collected gold?
就是为了当艰难时刻来临时..
So when hard times come...
- 他们可以...-兄弟，别担心
- ...they can... - Shanti Bhai, don't worry at all.
哈尔沙德和阿什温就像我的家人一样
Harshad and Ashwin are like family to me.
是的，但我警告过哈尔沙德
Yes. But I had warned Harshad...
要小心
...to be careful.
你知道的... 在下雨的时候..
You know how it is... When it rains...
即使你有伞
...even if you have an umbrella...
你还是有可能在光滑的路上摔倒
...you can still fall on a slippery road.
我不是唯一一个亏钱的，整个市场都在下滑
I'm not the only one, the entire market has slipped.
当天上下着钱的时候，没有人会打开雨伞
And when it was raining money, no one bothered opening their umbrellas.
- 每个人都忙着淋湿-但现在所有的东西都被冲走了！
- Everyone was busy getting drenched. - But everything has washed away now!
什么都没有了
- There's nothing left.
我们现在和我们家的金子坐在这里！
We are sitting here with our family gold!
请冷静..
Please calm down...
(苏雷什)“这是常有的事”
[Suresh] 'It happens.'
对不起，苏雷什兄弟
I'm sorry, Suresh Bhai.
苏雷什兄弟，这些是我的财产证明
Suresh Bhai, these are my property papers.
这套公寓和这块金子..
The flat and this gold...
应该能抵七十万的债务
...should cover your seven lakhs.
你在说什么？
What are you saying, Shanti Bhai?
我不需要这些财产证明
There's no need for these property papers.
钱又不会跑？
The money isn't running away, is it?
那样的话，你为什么不重新启动我们的交易帐户呢？
Well, in that case, why don't you restart our trading account?
我也许可以早点还给你
I might be able to pay you back sooner.
听着哈尔沙德
Look Harshad...
你在三年内赚了三十万卢比
...you earned three lakhs in three years.
却在10分钟内损失了100万卢比
And you lost 10 lakhs in 10 minutes.
所以，很明显，股票市场不是那么容易..
So, obviously the stock market is not that easy...
能让你马上就能进去开始印钱
...that you will get in and start minting right away.
因此，除非你还完这一百万，否则你的交易帐户就一直暂停
So, until you return the full amount, your trading account will remain suspended.
[苏雷什]“这个孩子很聪明，但他在跑起来之前”
[Suresh] 'The boy is smart but he wants to charge ahead.'
要先学会走路..
He needs to learn how to walk first...
你怎么还没睡？
How come you're still up?
睡不着
No, well...
我想我吃得太多了
...I think I ate too much.
我已经吃了些消化药
I did take some digestive.
你呢
You tell me.
你怎么醒了？
Why are you awake?
明天有个会议
There's a meeting tomorrow.
一旦我们的交易帐户重新开启
Once our trading account is up and running...
- ... 然后看...-哈尔沙德
- ...then see... - Harshad.
你总是在逆潮游泳
You always swim against the tide.
白天做梦，晚上熬夜
You dream during the day and stay up at night.
除非你保持清醒，你的交易账户就不会重启
It's not like your trading account will restart if you stay awake.
去睡觉，好吗？
Go to sleep. Okay?
你害怕了，是不是？
You're scared, aren't you?
害怕我们可能又要离开孟买了？
...that we might have to leave Bombay again?
不... 不是那样的
No... Nothing like that.
爸爸
Pappa.
永远不要对黑夜撒谎
Never lie to the night.
黑夜掌握着我们所有的秘密
The night holds all our secrets.
我的股票经纪人儿子..
My stock-broker son...
什么时候变成诗人了？
...when did you turn into a poet?
只要我还活着..
As long as I live...
我不会让孟买证券交易所离开我的视线
...I won't let Bombay Stock Exchange out of my sight.
交易所就在这里，在孟买
And BSE is right here, in Bombay.
所以，爸爸，快去睡吧
So Mr. Shantilal, go sleep in peace.
所以，尚蒂拉尔先生... ..
[Harshad] 'So Mr. Shantilal...'
如果我们早点知道的话，还可以把他送到医院去
Had we known earlier, we could've taken him to the hospital.
我们怎么付得起医院的账单？
And how would we afford the hospital bills?
也许这样更好
It's for the better.
他在睡梦中安详地去世
He passed away in his sleep peacefully.
他最放不下的是你
He was most worried about you.
担忧是通往火葬场的必经之路
'Worrying is a sure path to your pyre'.
这是山特拉尔先生常说的话
That's what Mr. Shantilal used to say.
我知道电信公司和 Zenith 公司会迅速崛起
I knew that Telco and Zenith would surge.
我本来可以赚一大笔钱的
I could have made a solid profit.
我要去斯里兰卡找份工作
I'm getting a job in Sri Lanka.
我在认真考虑
I'm seriously considering it.
现在正是我需要你的时候，你却打算离开我？
This is the time to stay together and you are also planning to leave me?
还有呢？
'Also'?
爸爸已经..
Pappa has already...
我们有头脑，你知道我们可以做到的
See, we have the brains. You know we can do this.
我已经预测到了这些股票的涨跌
I had predicted the rise and fall of all these shares.
这个纸上交易..
This paper-trading...
就像在街角的小店里看板球比赛
...is like watching cricket at a corner store...
然后给加瓦斯卡指示
...and giving instructions to Gavaskar.
你自己走上三柱门，就被保龄球打中了
Step onto the wicket yourself, and you're bowled.
如果我有钱，我就不会比加瓦斯卡少了
If I had the money, I'd be no less than Gavaskar here.
但是我们没有钱！
But we don't have the money!
哈尔沙德兄弟，好久不见
Harshad Bhai, it's been a while.
来三杯好茶
Three specials.
今天我请客喝茶
Tea is on me today.
你上次给我的情报，效果很好
The tip you gave me last time, it worked wonders.
感谢上帝，我赚了很多钱
By God's grace, I earned a lot.
也许你已经厌倦了市场，但是请继续给我们提供情报
Maybe you are fed up with the market... ...but don't stop giving us tips.
至少我们的口袋会满满的！
At least our pockets will be full!
- 你说什么?-嘿，维卡斯！
-[Vikas] 'What say?' - Hey, Vikas!
来了! 把茶给他们，记在我的账上
Coming! Give them the tea and put it on my tab.
我们提供咨询服务吧
Let's start consulting.
- 什么?-一家咨询公司
- What? - A consultancy firm.
你说真的吗？
Are you serious?
听着，我们没钱..
Look, we don't have money...
我们的脸也不会吸引任何人
...and our faces aren't going to attract any.
所以，让我们的大脑开始工作吧
So, let's put our brains to work.
如果我们能把5卢比变成10卢比，我们至少能赚50派沙的佣金
If we can turn five rupees into ten for anybody we'll make at least 50 paise in commission.
股市崩盘之后，是一个非常危险的地方
After the crash, the stock market is a very risky place.
- 我觉得这不是个好提议-不..
- I don't think it's a good proposal. - No...
这不是股市的错..
That's not the stock market's fault...
这就像一场蛇梯棋游戏
...that it is like a game of snakes and ladders.
听我说完，就这一次，掷骰子..
Hear me out Dhruv Bhai, just this once, roll the dice...
谁知道呢，说不定你正好落在通往顶端的梯子上呢！
Who knows, you might just land on the ladder to the top!
如果再次下跌怎么办？
And what if it slips again?
还能再跌多少？
How much lower can it slip, Dhruv Bhai?
市场已经跌到谷底，唯一的出路就是上涨
The market is at its rock-bottom. The only way now, is up.
我们的公司是一家新公司
And look, ours is a new company.
我们不会因为一分钱就毁了我们的名声，对吧？
We won't ruin our reputation for the sake of pennies, will we?
这比市场崩溃的风险更大
That's riskier than the market crashing.
- 阿什温，告诉我真相-好的
- Ashwin, tell me the truth. - Yes.
我是你牺牲的第一只羔羊吗？
Am I the first lamb you're sacrificing?
- 水牛-什么？
- Buffalo. - What?
- 对牛弹琴-什么意思？
- Singing to a buffalo. - What do you mean?
“真的，阿什温! ”
[Harshad] 'Really, Ashwin!'
和一个对市场不感兴趣的人谈话有什么意义呢？
What's the point of talking to someone who is not interested in the markets?
这难道不像对牛弹琴吗？
Isn't it like singing to a buffalo?
我没告诉过你吗? 这些特许会计师生活在对红线的恐惧中
Didn't I tell you? These Chartered Accountants live in fear of the red line.
他是未来的客户，哈尔沙德
He's a future client, Harshad.
- 你怎么能这么说我们的客户?-什么客户？
- How can you say such things about a client? - What client?
牛还没出生，你就开始用牛奶庆祝？
The buffalo isn't born yet, and you're celebrating with buttermilk?
客户是投资人
A client is one who invests money.
但他对任何投资都不感兴趣
But he is not interested in making any investment.
你找到一个客户了吗？
Have you managed to find even a single client?
我找到一个客户，他投资了45万卢比
I've found a client who's investing 4.5 lakhs.
那么，你就保持安静
[Ashwin] 'So, you just stay quiet.'
兄弟，别理他，他是个急性子
Dhruv Bhai, ignore him, he's hot-headed.
请不要让这件事影响我们的友谊
Please don't let this come in the way of our friendship.
听着，这是你的钱，你的愿望
Look. It's your money, your wish.
- 毕竟，谁挥动棍子，谁就能得到水牛-嘿！
- After all, he who wields the stick, gets the buffalo. - Hey!
请不要再说那些关于“水牛”的格言了
Stop with the 'buffalo' sayings. Please.
我还没有拒绝
I haven't refused yet.
10万卢比
One lakh.
我可以投资10万卢比
I can invest up to one lakh.
“如果你把我带到梯子那儿，我们就再滚一次”
[Dhruv] 'If you get me to the ladder, we'll roll again.'
“你那些水牛说的话可能会让我们损失惨重! ”
[Ashwin] 'Your buffalo sayings could have cost us heavily!'
你不是也一样! 你设下了一个45万卢比的陷阱
You are no less! You laid a good '4.5 lakh' trap.
那不是陷阱，我们真的有四十五万卢比
That wasn't a trap, we do have 4.5 lakhs.
嘿! 过来
Hey! Come here.
从哪来的钱？
From where?
- 我岳父岳母给的-什么意思？
- From my in-laws. - Meaning?
我和迪皮卡的父亲谈过了
Meaning, I have spoken to Deepika's father.
- 你岳父?-是的
- Your father-in-law? - Yes.
- 但是...-是从他的退休基金里拿的
- But... - It was from his retirement fund.
如果财富女神敲我的门，我怎么会不开门呢？
If the Goddess of wealth knocks at my door, won't I open it?
他主动提出，我接受了
He offered, I accepted.
谁知道呢，我岳父的钱可能会给我们带来成功
And who knows, my father-in-law's money might bring us success.
对吧？
Right?
到底什么是成功? 失败后的下一个篇章
What is success, after all? The next chapter after failure.
说得好，我的塔拉克 · 梅塔！
Well said, my Taarak Mehta!
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔
Harshad Mehta.
阿什温 · 梅塔
Ashwin Mehta.
“高摩，这是什么意思? ”
[Suresh] 'Growmore. What does it mean?'
“高”意味着“进步” ，“摩”意味着“很多”
'Grow' means 'to progress'. 'More' means 'a lot'.
进步很多，繁荣很多
Progress a lot. Prosper a lot.
现在英文名字很流行，对吧？
English names are all the rage these days, right?
看看苏雅塔钢铁公司他们改名为种马钢铁..
Look at Sujata Steels. They changed their name to Stallion Steels...
两个月后，它们的股价从7卢比涨到了12卢比
...and in 2 months, their price rose from seven to twelve rupees.
人们更倾向于相信英文名字，不是吗？
People tend to trust English names more, isn't it?
我已经把帐算清了
Well, I've settled the accounts.
我们还欠你一点... 很快会还给你的
We owe you a little more... We'll return it soon.
没必要担心
There is no need to worry.
那么告诉我，你未来的计划是什么？
So tell me, what are your future plans?
你有一些投资人，对吧？
You have some investors, right?
我的意思是..
What I mean is...
投资需要经纪人对吧？
...to invest, you'd need a broker, right?
没错，我们会在某个地方成为次级经纪人
That's right. We'll become sub-brokers somewhere.
在别的地方? 为什么不在这里？
Somewhere? Why not here?
你已经暂停了我们的交易账户，不是吗？
But you've suspended our trading account, right?
所以很明显我们不能在这里做次级经纪人
So obviously we can't be sub-brokers here.
你的交易帐户今天恢复
Your trading account resumes today.
不要想太多，今天是吉祥的日子
Don't think too much. Today is an auspicious day.
好吧从今天开始你就是我的代理人
Okay. From today, I make you my sub-broker.
还有别的事吗？
Anything else?
那么…
So...
你的地址在哪里？
What's your address?
我到哪里去找你喝杯茶？
Where do I visit you for a cup of tea?
我在这栋楼里有八个办公室..
I have eight offices in this building...
但是你很幸运..
But you are very lucky...
你父亲的旧办公室还可以使用
...that your father's old office is available.
我知道这看起来有点乱
I know it looks a bit messy.
但是，我会打扫干净，焕然一新
But, I'll get it cleaned and it'll be spanking new.
租金是多少？
What's the rent?
以前的房客付250卢比
[Landlord] 'The previous tenant used to pay 250 rupees.'
你们就像一家人，租金是可以商量的
'You're like family. It's negotiable.'
重要的是所有的纺织品贸易商在这里都有办公室..
What's important is that all textile traders have offices here...
你可以得到你需要的一切，比如纽扣，线，针..
You can get everything you need. Buttons, thread, needles...
我们经营的不是纺织品
Our business is not textiles.
但是你父亲..
But your father...
他当时是做纺织生意的
...he did run a textile business then...
但我们是在股票市场
...but we are in the share market.
哈尔沙德，他开价500卢比租金和5000押金
Harshad, he is quoting 500 rupees rent and a deposit of 5000.
不管多少钱，我们就租这里
Whatever it is, let's take it.
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
你为什么要搬进你爸爸的办公室？
Why did you have to move into that same office?
那个办公室什么也没给我们
That office has given us nothing.
事实上，它夺走了我们拥有的一切
In fact, it took away everything we had.
- 请不要担心...-我为什么不应该担心？
- Please don't worry... - Why shouldn't I worry?
- 叫什么来着? 坏...-坏运气
- What is it called? Bad... - Bad luck.
- 对吧?-是的
- Right? - Yes.
不会出任何差错
Nothing will go wrong.
那里所有的商人都在赚钱
All traders there are minting money.
来，读读这篇文章
Here, read this paper.
- 我不看-你的星座是什么? 你不是白羊座的吗
- I don't want to. - What's your zodiac? Aren't you an Aries...
嘿! 你一大早去哪儿了？
Hey! Where did you go early in the morning?
调查市场
Fact-finding.
- 调查 -调查? 调查茶叶？
- Research. - Research? Researching tea?
我们现在要开茶摊了吗？
Are we starting a tea stall now?
- 妈妈，给我倒杯茶-好的
- Mummy, get me a cup of tea please? - Yes.
我们应该投资茶叶
We should invest in tea.
嘿! 就因为一个卖茶的把价格提高了50派沙..
Hey! Just because a tea seller increased the price by 50 paise...
现在你认为股票市场会因此而繁荣吗？
...now you think the stock market will boom because of this?
我不是在说零钱，我刚刚和来自肯尼亚的哈里什谈过
I'm not talking about loose change. I've just spoken to Harish, the one from Kenya.
那又怎样？
So?
你知道世界上哪个国家生产的茶叶最多吗？
Do you know which country produces the most tea in the world?
- 中国-不是！
- China. - Rubbish!
- 为什么?-是非洲
- Why? - It's Africa.
世界上百分之三十以上的茶叶产自非洲
More than thirty percent of the world's tea is produced in Africa.
斯里兰卡排名第二，印度排名第四
Sri Lanka is in second position and India comes fourth.
很高兴知道这一点，但这跟我们有什么关系呢？
That's good to know but how does it matter to us?
这很重要，兄弟
It matters a lot, brother.
"Mavtho"改变了整个游戏规则
Mavtho has changed the whole game this year.
什么是 Mavtho？
What's Mavtho?
非季节性降雨
Unseasonal rainfall.
这使得非洲的茶叶产量大幅下降
This has dropped tea production in Africa considerably.
是吗？
Is it?
- 现在他们不能满足需求了-没错
- Now they won't be able to meet the demand. - Correct.
那么，谁会从中受益呢
So, who is going to benefit from it? Uhh...
- 印度-没错
- India. - Yes, right.
看看这个，印度今年的茶叶出口量将翻一番
Look at this, Indian tea exports are about to double this year.
- 所以利润也会翻倍-翻倍
- So, the profits too will double. - Double.
- 所以，我们应该大量投资塔塔茶叶公司-还有其他公司
- So, let's invest big in Tata Tea. - There are other companies too.
还有哈里森、马拉雅拉姆、麦克劳德、拉塞尔
There's Harrisons Malayalam... McLeod Russell.
麦克劳德每年支付20% 的股息
McLeod pays a 20 percent dividend every year.
但它的股价只有14卢比
But its share price is only 14 rupees.
如果我们投资它，一定会获利
If we invest in it, we're sure to make a profit.
那么，你的速度怎么样？
So, what's your speed?
先生，我每分钟能打80个字
Sir, I can type 80 words per minute.
好吧，你有打字机吗？
Okay. Do you own a typewriter?
没有，先生，你得提供一台打字机
No, sir. You will have to give me a typewriter.
不不
No, no...
如果你想在这里工作，你就得有自己的打字机
If you want to work here, you'll have to get your own typewriter.
我可以输入印地语，英语，Gujarati 和马拉地语
I can type in Hindi, English, Gujarati and Marathi.
你好，雷贝罗，坐下
Yes, Rebello, sit down.
雷贝罗，你的打字速度怎么样？
Rebello, what's your typing speed?
- 每分钟四十个 -才四十个？
- Forty. - Just forty?
- 是的，先生 -我手写都比你快
- Yes, sir. - I write faster than that by hand.
但是我会进步的，先生，我每天都在练习
But I will improve, sir. I practice every day.
- 在哪里练习?-在家里
- Where? - At home.
- 你有打字机吗? -有
- Do you own a typewriter? - Yes.
亲爱的拉瓦尔先生...
[Harshad] 'Dear Mr. Rawal...'
“我们高摩咨询公司想邀请您...”
'...we at Growmore Consultants would like to invite you...'
在我们这里开一个交易账户
'...to open a trading account with us.'
“在这里，我们可以把你多余的钱…”
'Here we can park your surplus money into the stock markets...'
放在我们的投资组合管理计划下投入股市
'...under our portfolio management scheme.'
我们的商业战略建立在这样一个信念之上:
'Our business strategy rests on the belief...'
我们可以为您提供优质服务和更高的回报
'...that we can provide you with good service and higher returns.'
“哈尔沙德 · 梅塔敬上，来自高摩咨询”
'Yours truly, Harshad Mehta for Growmore.'
你到底在说什么
[Rahil] 'What're you even saying?'
我告诉过你，我听不懂
I told you, this would go past my head.
看到没? 我是对的
See? I was right.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我怎么能卖掉我没有的股份呢？
How can I sell shares that I don't have?
- 这叫做空？ -也许吧
- It's called selling short. - That may be so.
- 怎么做到的?-你没有股份..
- But how is it done? - Look, you don't have the shares...
但是管理你交易账户的经纪人有很多股
...but the broker who handles your trading account has plenty shares.
让我们假设... 信实公司今天股价是100卢比..
Let's assume... Reliance is 100 rupees today...
你觉得它可能会跌下来
...and you think it might drop.
所以你让你的经纪人以你的名义卖出10股，每股100卢比
So you ask your broker to sell 10 shares on your behalf, for 100 rupees each.
所以他卖10股，每股100卢比他赚多少钱？
So he sells 10 shares for 100 rupees each. How much does he make?
一千卢比
A thousand rupees.
那1000块是我的吗？
Will that 1000 be mine?
还不是，没那么简单
Not yet. It's not so easy.
- 首先你得换掉他卖给你的股票对吧?-是的
- First, you have to replace the shares that he sold for you, correct? - Yes.
这种结算周期在股票市场持续14天
And this settlement cycle lasts 14 days in the share market.
现在，在这14天里，股价可能会波动
Now in these 14 days, the share price can fluctuate.
可能会达到110,120,80,90等等
It could go to 110, 120, 80, 90, etcetera.
现在假设股票价值达到80..
Now say, the day the share value is at 80...
你让你的经纪人帮你买十股
...you ask your broker to buy ten shares for you...
他花了多少钱买的？
...how much does he pay for them?
- 800?-是的
- 800? - Yes.
这就是所谓的“简化交易”
This is called 'squaring off a transaction'.
1000美元卖出，800美元买回，利润是多少？
Sold for 1000, bought back at 800, what's the profit?
200? 200的利润？
200? A profit of 200?
不完全是，还要扣除一些佣金
Not entirely, some is deducted as commission.
剩下的就是你的了
The rest is yours.
这就像打板球一样，不是吗？
This is like betting in cricket, isn't it?
你把赌注押在可能会输的那一方，输了你就赢了
You bet on the losing team, the team loses and you make a profit.
但是如果球队赢了呢？
But what if the team wins?
如果股价上涨怎么办？
What if the share price goes up?
但是如果你知道球队的历史..
But if you know the team's history...
球员的记录，以及球场的状况等等
...the player's record, the condition of the pitch...
那就不是赌博，而是经过深思熟虑的预测
...then it's not betting. It's a calculated prediction.
你确定吗？
Are you sure about this?
要相信哈尔沙德敏锐的商业头脑
Trust Harshad's sharp business sense.
它是超越所有人的最佳头脑
It slices past the best of them.
[普拉那夫]‘普通客户，重点客户……’
[Pranav] 'Plain papadum, pickled papadum.'
‘朴实的客户，街上的客户... ’朴实的意思是... 家人和朋友..
'Plain papadum, pickled papad...' Plain meaning... family and friends..
还有街上的客户? 你在外面加的联系人
And pickled? The contacts you add outside.
半年过去了，你却只有几个本土客户
In six months, all you have are a few home-grown clients...
没有一个是从别的地方来的
...and not a single pickled one from elsewhere.
你这样还能走多远？
How far will you go like this?
普拉那夫兄弟，我对流动的客户没兴趣
Pranav Bhai, I am not interested in rolling papadums.
我想直接煎一下，配上番茄洋葱一起吃
I want to directly fry and eat them with a tomato-onion garnish.
你现在是在找公司客户吗？
Are you asking for corporate clients now?
你肯定能给我弄到一些，你现在对企业界很熟悉了
You can surely get me a few. You're well-versed with the corporate world now.
想都别想，公司客户不会来这里的
Don't even think about it, Corporate clients won't come here.
但是也有几只有钱的鸟，我们可以为他们撒一些种子
But there are a few wealthy birds. We can spread some Seed for them.
但是，他们不会给你的鸽子笼增光添彩
But hey! They won't grace this pigeonhole of yours.
你的贫穷将困扰他们富有的灵魂
Your poverty will trouble their rich souls.
好吧，你说怎样就怎样
Okay. I'll do whatever you say.
你的英语说得怎么样？
How well does English roll off your tongue?
我的公司是刚成立不久的
My company is relatively new.
但是我对市场有新的看法
But I have a fresh approach towards the market.
我一直为我所有的客户
I've been consistently delivering 37 percent profit...
保持着37% 的利润
...to all my clients for the last 10 months.
请看
Have a look.
但是才这么点钱，利润高又能怎样呢？
But the base capital is quite low. How does the profit matter?
先生，这么说吧
Sir, look at it this way. The glass is half full.
你有没有见过一个10卢比的投资回报14卢比？
Have you ever seen a return of 14 rupees on an investment of 10?
不知不觉，一百万卢比就会变成一百四十万卢比
Before you know it, ten lakhs will turn into 14.
我可以轻而易举地为你提供纯粹的利润
I can serve you pure profit on a platter.
股票市场不是阿里巴巴的洞穴，不是吗？
Share market isn't Ali Baba's cave, is it?
你说“芝麻开门” ，宝藏的大门就会打开？
You'll say 'Open Sesame' and the door to the treasure will open?
完全正确，这既不是洞穴，也不是魔法
You're absolutely right. This is neither a cave nor is it magic.
这就是我们必须改变的观念
And that's the very perception we have to change.
这一切都是需要研究和分析的
See, it's all about research and analysis.
只有进行适当的研究和分析，才能在市场上投资你的钱
We conduct proper research and analysis, and only then we invest your money in the market.
什么样的研究？
What kind of research?
我说的研究是指公司的资产负债表，未来的计划..
By research I mean, the company's balance sheet, its future plans...
还有一些只有少数人知道的重要机密信息
...and some crucial confidential information that only a few know about.
长话短说..
To cut a long story short...
上个月... 放松，小心点
Last month... Easy, be careful.
如果我一个月前告诉你..
What if I had told you a month back...
印度国家板球队将会赢得世界杯
...to bet on the Indian cricket team because it's going to win the World Cup.
你会这么做吗？
Would you have done it?
但是现在看看，印度已经赢得了世界杯
But now look, India has won the World Cup.
现在想想，那些在印度上下注的人..
Now think about this. The ones who did bet on India...
他们一定发了大财！
What a fortune they must have made!
记住一件事，哈尔沙德..
Remember one thing. Harshad...
是交易所里的的卡皮尔・德夫（板球运动员？）
...is the Kapil Dev of BSE.
别想太多了，让我们为此干杯
Don't think too much. Let's drink to this.
- 干杯-干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
过来，我有话跟你说
Come here. I need to talk to you.
失陪，先生们
Carry on gentlemen.
我再也忍受不了了，所以就跳了进去，对不起
I couldn't bear it any longer, so I jumped in. Sorry.
现在我的阿里巴巴，去让你的40个盗贼和钱打交道吧..
Now my Ali Baba, go keep your 40 thieves engaged with money...
我去找我的宝贝们
I'll go get my honey...
亲爱的，我讨厌眼泪但我喜欢欢呼声！
Darling, I hate tears But I love cheers!
耶！
Yeah!
来，来..
Come, come...
先生们，来见见我的小蝴蝶
Gentlemen, meet my butterflies.
蝴蝶们，去见见你们的大黄蜂
Butterflies, meet your bumblebees.
你为什么把腰带系这么紧? 现在是时候松开了
Why are you tightening your trousers? It's time to loosen them now.
嘿！
Hey!
废物
He's completely useless.
你这个傻瓜！
You're a fool!
你已经变成了一匹驮马
You've become a workhorse.
聪明一点！
Be smarter!
你什么时候离开聚会的？
When did you leave the party?
- 我走之前没告诉你吗?-那么早？
- Didn't I tell you before leaving? - That early?
- 我是个有家室的男人，我不能这么做-啊？
- I'm a family man, I can't do this. - Huh?
是的，我们有家庭，我们不能这么做
Yes, we have families. We can't do this.
嘿，家庭主妇们! 他们都是有家室的男人
Hey, family wallahs! All those were also family men.
阿什温，这就是现在经营生意的方式，只有混在一起才能赚钱
Ashwin, this is how you run a business. You will earn money only if you mingle.
其中四个人准备投资一百万卢比但是他..
Four of them were ready to invest ten lakhs, but him...
- 顾家男人-就四个？
- Family man. - Just four?
你不是说有40个人吗？
Didn't you say there were 40 people?
- 这是重点吗?-看看这个
-[Pranav] 'How does it matter?' - Look at this.
芝麻开门
Open Sesame.
这是什么？
What is it?
“戈瓦尔丹”
"Govardhan."
“戈尔丹达斯”
"Gordhandas."
“马尼拉”
"Manilal."
”瓦桑特”
"Vasant."
瓦桑特给你钱了? ！
Vasant gave you money?!
阿里巴巴和大盗，哈尔沙德和高摩投资
Ali Baba and thieves galore, Harshad and Growmore.
跟我击个掌
Give me a high five.
达拉尔女士你知道..
Ms. Dalal, do you know...
孟买证券交易所有多少层吗？
...how many floors there are in the Bombay Stock Exchange?
28层
Twenty-eight.
在这28层楼之间跑来跑去
Running between these 28 floors and gathering...
每天的每一点信息都可能是你的工作
...every bit of information every day could be your job.
现在听起来还令人兴奋吗？
Does it still sound exciting?
是的
Yes. Yes, it does.
而且，我现在的工作也要经常到处跑，所以这根本不是问题
Also, I run around a lot in my current job so that shouldn't be a problem at all.
达拉尔女士，我真的很想知道
Ms. Dalal, I really want to know this.
为什么你想从事一个没有女人从事的职业？
Why do you want to take up a career in something where there are no women?
这很重要吗，先生？
Should that really matter, sir?
我的意思是，让我们从大局出发
I mean, let's look at the big picture.
我们打破的成见越多，社会得到的益处就越多
The more stereotypes we break, the more society benefits.
先生，我只想成为一名伟大的记者
Sir, I just want to be a great journalist.
回答你的问题，如果这能让我成为
And to answer your question, if that makes me...
第一位女性金融记者
...the first female financial journalist...
那我就更应该努力工作，出类拔萃了
...then it's all the more reason for me to work hard and excel.
事实上，这是一条人迹罕至的道路
The fact that it's a lesser-travelled road...
我不介意
...that, that doesn't bother me.
而且，这也意味着较少的薪水
Well, lesser-travelled roads would also mean less salary.
我们甚至不能支付你目前酒店工作收入的一半
We can't even pay you half of what you are getting in your current hotel job.
如果我在金融部门工作..
Well, if I am working in the finance sector...
我至少需要足够的钱来管理我自己的财务
...I will at least need enough to manage my own finances.
那要多少钱？
And, how much would that be?
嗯..
Uhm...
你们这些家伙怎么能泡出这么难喝的茶..
You guys make such pathetic tea...
连饼干都对它不屑一顾
...that even the biscuit shies away.
如果你要上凉茶的话..
If you are going to serve cold tea...
那你为什么要把茶叶煮到焦？
...then why do you boil the tea leaves till they burn?
这茶是谁泡的？
Who makes this tea?
等一下，让我告诉你该怎么泡茶
Wait a minute. Let me tell you how tea is made.
首先，烧水的时候不加茶叶
First, boil some water without tea leaves.
水开了之后加入一些豆蔻，生姜和罗邦戈
Add some cardamom, some ginger and some lobongo.
- 那是什么?-丁香..
- What's that? - Cloves...
- 那就直接说丁香 -好的，主人，丁香
- Then say that. - Okay, my master. Cloves.
水开后，加入茶叶
Once the water boils, add the tea leaves.
不要把茶叶煮熟，好吗？
Don't boil the tea leaves to death. Okay?
然后加一点牛奶，很简单，茶就好了
Then add a little milk. Simple. Tea is ready.
- 什么时候加糖?-最后
- And when do we add sugar? - At the end.
明白了吗? 现在把这个给泡茶的人
Did you get it? Now give this to the one who makes tea.
你留着吧，先生，他不识字
Keep it with you, sir. He doesn't know to read.
我会向他解释的
I will explain it to him.
嘿，带上这个！
Hello, take this with you!
- 德巴什? -先生
- Debashis? - Sir.
这是苏切塔 · 达拉尔
This is Sucheta Dalal.
是的，先生，你告诉过我
Oh, yes, sir. You told me.
给她介绍下孟买证券交易所，好吗？
Show her the Bombay Stock Exchange, yeah?
好的，先生
Sure sir.
- 一切顺利-谢谢，先生
- All the best. - Thank you, sir.
你的左边是印度国家银行
To your left, is the SBI.
人们在那里存钱，然后在证交所赔钱
People save money there and lose it here at the BSE.
好了，我们到了
Okay. Here we are.
顺便说一下，孟买最好的三明治在这里有卖
By the way, Bombay's best sandwiches are sold here.
除此之外，还有免费的薄荷酱和市场八卦
And with that, mint chutney and market-gossip for free.
来吧
Come.
- 我们先去见阿加瓦尔先生，然后再去见其他人-好的
- First, we'll meet Agarwal sir and then the rest. - Okay.
- 嘿！吉涅什 -德巴什
- Hey, Jignesh Bhai. - Debashis Bhai.
-兄弟，今天市场很震撼! -是吗？
- Debashis Bhai, the market is rocking today! - Is it?
指数一路飙升，今天一定血赚
The index went through the roof of BSE. We will make a solid profit today.
看，在追求利润的过程中，别忘了你的报纸文章，Jignesh Bhai
Look, in the pursuit of profit, don't forget your newspaper article, Jignesh Bhai.
你什么时候能从苏拉特给我买到那些特别的糖果？
And when will you get me those special sweets from Surat?
只要你一句话，老板
Just say the word, boss.
我将乘早班火车去接他们
I'll call for them by the morning train.
- 还需要什么吗?-不用了，谢谢
- Anything else? - Please, thank you.
- 好的再见-再见
- Okay, then. Bye. - Bye.
他是财经记者吉涅什
That's the financial reporter of Ahmedabad Samachar. Jignesh.
怎么了? 你在看什么？
What happened? What are you looking at?
哦，好的! 来吧
Oh, okay! Come.
看，无论是记者还是财经类报纸... ... 都不可能在1200到1500卢比之间存活
Look, neither reporters nor financial newspapers... can survive at 1200 to 1500 rupees
这就是这个系统的工作原理
This is how the system works.
他们都和商人一起吃饭、睡觉、拉屎
They all eat, sleep and shit together with the traders.
他们获得了如此多的内部消息，以至于在几年内，每个人都安定下来了
They get so much insider news that in a few years, everyone is well-settled.
- 你也炒股吗?-不... 我没有耐心
- Do you trade too? - No... I don't have patience.
炒股就像眼睁睁地看着油漆干枯或者草长出来
Trades are always like watching paint dry or grass grow.
我宁愿投资钻石
I would rather invest in diamonds.
那么，玩钻石的家伙在达拉尔街干什么？
So, what's a diamond guy doing in Dalal street?
- 我所有的消息来源都在这儿-啊
- All my sources are here. - Ah.
来吧
Come.
我们在Blowcast陷得太深了
We went too deep into Blowcast.
我们在正确的时间投入了正确的金额
We had invested the right amount at the right time.
整个市场都在上涨，但我们完蛋了
The entire market is on a high. But we're screwed.
随它去吧，过去的就过去了
Let it be. What's gone is gone.
听着，如果我们必须这么做，就不能完全靠自己
Look, if we have to do this, we can't do it by ourselves.
我们需要员工，我们需要有经验的人
We need staff. We need someone who has some experience.
一个知道怎么投资的人..
Someone who knows to play the ring...
还能处理后勤和账务
...and who can also handle the back office and accounts.
总之，我们需要一个有团队精神的人，兄弟
In short, we need a team player, brother.
我认识一个这样的多面手
I know one such all-rounder.
你是嗑药了还是把我当傻瓜？
Are you on drugs or do you take me for a fool?
你要我辞去安巴拉尔邦主的工作..
You are asking me to quit my job with Ambalal saheb...
为你工作，薪水却更低？
...and work for you at a lesser pay?
你喜欢为花生工作吗？
You enjoy working for peanuts?
别管薪水和佣金了，把精力集中在利润上
Forget salary and commission. Concentrate on the profit.
股票市场是一口深井..
The share market is a deep well...
可以满足整个国家对金钱的渴望
...that can quench the entire nation's thirst for money.
我想跳进这口井里
And I want to dive into this well.
我想深入研究
I want to go very deep.
听着，我想创造历史
Look, I want to create history.
历史并不容易创造，它需要人们的信念和支持
And history is not easy to make. It needs the conviction and support of people.
我想建立一支100人的军队... ... 他们愿意为我付出100% 的努力
I want to build an army of a 100... who are willing to give me their 100 percent.
那么我百分之一千零一肯定，我们能够创造历史
Then I'm a thousand and one per cent sure that we'll create history.
我的军队只能有一个指挥官，布尚·巴特
There can only be one commander to my army. Bhushan Bhatt.
我们是老搭档了
We are old partners.
你是想让我做合伙人吗？
Are you offering me a partnership?
你想要什么就拿什么，公司是你的了
Take whatever you want. The company is yours.
但首先，请接受我的提议，与我携起手来
But first, accept my offer and join hands with me.
[苏切塔]“当我忙于了解股票市场的世界时... ... ”
[Sucheta] 'While I was busy understanding the world of the share market...'
“ ... ... 哈沙德正忙着让股票市场成为他的世界”
'...Harshad was busy making the share market his world.'
他在玩这个游戏，而我还在学
'He was playing the game, I was still learning it.'
慢慢地，他的视野开始开阔起来
'Slowly but surely, his horizons began to widen.'
现在，不仅仅是一场比赛，他看到了整个比赛场地
'Now, more than just one game, he was looking at the whole playing field.'
很快，他的梦想就会超越这枚戒指
'Soon, his dreams would outgrow the ring.'
但是在这个圈子里，有一个领袖，黑眼镜蛇，也就是马努·蒙德拉
'But in this ring, there was a ringmaster. Black Cobra. That is, Manu Mundra.'
市场随着马努的曲调起舞
'The market danced to Manu Bhai's tunes.'
即使是印度最大的公司也担心蒙德拉的决定
'Even the biggest companies in India feared Mundra's decisions.'
在市场上有一只
'And in the market, there was one mongoose...
能对付眼镜蛇的猫鼬
...who could take on the cobra.'
好的，我会的，好的
Okay, I'll do it. Okay.
哈沙德，是吉尼斯打来的
Harshad, it was Jignesh on the phone.
一个经纪人的会员卡正在被拍卖，你怎么看？
A broker's membership card is being auctioned. What do you say?
有什么好说的，你说吧
What's there to say. Go ahead.
我已经向帕里克寻求赞助了
I've already spoken to Parekh Bhai for sponsorship.
- 钱会安排好的-很好
- The money will be arranged. - Good.
茶
Tea.
克萨里旅游公司的人打电话来了
The people from Kesari Tours had called.
我们十二月份去西姆拉吧？
Let's go to Shimla in December?
你听到妈妈说什么了吗？
Did you hear what mummy said?
她想在12月份去西姆拉
She wants to go to Shimla in December.
告诉她，她会冻僵的！
Tell her she will freeze!
十二月份人们从四面八方赶来看雪
Duffer, in December people come from all over to see the snowfall.
- 十二月是个好时机-是吗？
- December is the right time. - Right?
- 是啊-价格也很合理
- Yeah. - Even the cost is reasonable.
他们还有一个素食厨师，所以我们可以吃古吉拉特食物
And they also have a vegetarian cook. So, we can have Gujarati food.
太好了，那我们一路上都吃虾肉
That's great. Then we'll have Shrikhand-Poori all the way.
让他们把细节发过来
Ask them to send the details.
去吧，打开收音机，该听爸爸的新闻了，去吧
Go, turn on the radio. It's time for Pappa's news. Go.
“ ... ... 这个令人悲伤的消息，英迪拉 · 甘地总理去世了”
[Newsreader] '...this sad news. Prime Minister Indira Gandhi is no more.'
甘地夫人被她的保安枪击
'Mrs. Gandhi was critically injured this morning...'
于今天早上受了重伤
'...after being shot by her security guards.'
她立即被送往全印度医学科学研究所
'She was immediately rushed to the All India Institute of Medical Sciences...'
但因伤势过重去世
'...where she succumbed to her injuries.'
据可靠消息称..
'According to reliable sources...'
“拉吉夫 · 甘地将宣誓就任下一任印度总理”
'...Rajiv Gandhi will be sworn in as the next Prime Minister of India.'
有人试图在总理府
There was an attempt...
刺杀甘地夫人
...on Mrs. Gandhi life at the Prime Minister's residence.
她立即被送往全印度医学科学研究所
She was taken to All India Institute of Medical Sciences immediately.
英迪拉 · 甘地总理之死
[Sucheta] 'Death of the Prime Minister Indira Gandhi...'
“ ... ... 是印度政治的一个分水岭”
[Sucheta] '...was a watershed event in Indian politics.'
[ Sucheta ]“这是意想不到的，令人震惊的... ... ”
[Sucheta] 'It was unexpected and shocking...'
[ Sucheta ]“它产生了强烈的反响... ... ”
[Sucheta] 'and it had violent repercussions...'
一方面，成千上万的人死于暴乱... ..
'On one hand, thousands of people were dying in riots...'
另一方面，整个国家对此视而不见
'...and on the other, the nation turned a blind eye to the situation.'
与此同时，拉吉夫•甘地(Rajiv Gandhi)正在被推举为总理
'Meanwhile, Rajiv Gandhi was being served up Prime Ministership on a platter...'
很多人不相信一个作为飞行员的男人..
'And many people refused to believe that a man who was just a pilot...'
“仅仅因为他的姓氏是甘地，就有能力领导这个国家”
'...would be able to lead the country just because his surname was Gandhi.'
这个飞行员能飞多久? 你觉得怎么样，马赫什瓦里？
How long will this pilot last? What do you think, Maheshwari?
最多到12月
Till December at best.
选举之后就没他的事了
He won't be there beyond the elections.
人们不相信这架飞机会起飞
People don't believe that this pilot will take off.
我认为时机已经成熟..
And I think the time is ripe...
解决所有的牛市交易
...to square off all the bull trades...
并在市场上占有一席之地
...and take positions in the market.
让我们改写游戏规则
Let's f*****g break the market.
阿什温，尽你所能从市场上撤出来
Bhai Ashwin, pull out all you can from the market.
这是一个灾难性下跌
It's a nosedive.
很快指数就会落入尘埃
Soon the index will be in the dust.
我们先让它恢复一点，然后再卖掉
Let's allow it to recover a little. Then we'll sell.
- 你怎么说，哈沙德?-‘你怎么想? ’
- What do you say, Harshad? -[Pranav] 'What do you think?'
这不是经济舱的飞机
This is not the economy class of an airplane.
国家的经济现在掌握在他的手中
The nation's economy is in his hands now.
很快，我们就会拿着乞讨用的碗在街上游荡
And soon, we will be roaming the market with begging bowls.
哈尔沙德，你有在听吗？
Harshad, are you even listening?
如果我说了，你会头疼的
If I say what I want, you'll get a headache.
- 还想听吗?-好吧
- Still want to hear it? - Okay.
我洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
市场上的马萨拉是用四种香料制成的
The masala of the market is created from four spices.
- 马萨拉?-是的
- Masala? - Yes.
首先，情报，或者信息，内幕交易，研究
Firstly, tip. Or information, insider trading, research.
现在给它增加一些风险
Now add some risk to it.
风险越高，市场越刺激
Higher the risk, spicier the market.
在这个混合物里加入一些情绪
Grind some passion into this mixture.
- 什么样的情绪?-激情
- What kind of passion? -[Harshad] 'Emotion.'
正如交易专家所言，“理解市场情绪”
As the trade pundits say, "Understand the sentiment of the market".
所以，理解这种情绪
So, understand the emotion.
现在再加上一点运气，就是这样，市场上的马萨拉已经准备好了
And now add a pinch of luck. There you go. The market's masala is ready.
他是做生意还是做饭? 阿什温？
Is he trading or cooking? Ashwin?
普拉纳夫，你的马萨拉太情绪化了
Pranav Bhai, your masala is too heavy on emotions.
人在情绪化的时候总是会犯错误
And man always makes mistakes when he is emotional.
现在是增加风险缓和的时候了
This is the time to add a tempering of risk.
现在不是卖的时候，是买的时候
This is not the time to sell. It's the time to buy.
这些熊市对市场的拉动力越小..
The lower these bears pull the market...
它就会反弹得越高
...the higher it will bounce.
一定会反弹的，看看这个
It will rebound. Look at this.
这个飞行员要飞得很高，我们也是
This pilot is going to fly high. And so are we.
普拉纳夫兄弟，我很少同意哈尔沙德的观点
Pranav Bhai, I rarely agree with Harshad.
但今天我同意
But today is one such day.
这就是你们的问题所在
This is exactly the problem with you Bulls.
公牛用希望杀死你
A Bull kills you with hope.
熊用恐惧杀死你
And a Bear kills you with fear.
看这个，读这个段落，看
Look at this. Read this paragraph. Look.
印地罗，Zuari Agro，SPIC
Indrol, Zuari Agro, SPIC.
你知道它们有多便宜吗？
Do you know how cheap they are?
一旦它们激增，就没有什么能够阻挡
Once they surge, there will be no stopping them.
你疯了吗? 这个国家正在燃烧
Are you crazy? The country is up in flames.
人们不是在开车，而是在焚烧汽车
People aren't driving cars. They're burning them.
在这样的时刻，你想投资石油，石油？
And at a time like this, you want to invest in oil, in petroleum?
我的朋友，不管怎样你都需要汽油，不管是开车还是烧车
My friend. You need petrol either way. Whether it is to drive a car, or to burn it.
别管情感价值了，看看真正的价值吧，亲爱的
Forget the sentimental value. Look at the real value, darling.
是的，这是确认的消息，英卓尔今天会跌到谷底
Yes, brother. This is confirmed news. Indrol will drown today.
谁在耍英卓尔？
Who's screwing with Indrol?
眼镜蛇! 眼镜蛇！
Cobra! Cobra!
他做空英卓尔，今天肯定会崩溃
He's short on Indrol. It will crash today for sure.
但是我们已经在这个事情上做了很长时间的准备
But we've taken a rather long position on it.
那又怎样，兄弟? 眼镜蛇的尾巴更长
So what, brother? The Cobra's tail is longer.
[ Bhushan ]‘相信我，收手吧，我们能承受一点损失’
[Bhushan] 'Trust me, let it go, we can bear a little loss.'
但我们没有足够的资金来持有头寸
But we don't have the cash to hold our position.
我们要抓住这条该死的眼镜蛇的长尾巴！
We'll catch this bloody Cobra by his long tail!
他会离开很长一段时间
He'll be gone for a long time.
- 让我们所有的客户都买入-什么? ！
- Let's ask all our clients to buy instead. -Huh?!
告诉我们所有的客户购买英卓尔，尽可能多的购买
Tell all our clients to buy Indrol. Buy as much as possible. Everything.
每个人都买一点，尽可能多买一点
Buy Indrol, everyone. Buy as much as possible.
- 嘿，萨钦兄弟...-你好，悉达基，最近怎么样？
- Hey, Sachin Bhau... - Hello, Siddeshji. How're you?
我有好消息要告诉你，瓦吉大哥，玩得开心吗？
I have good news for you. Vaghji Bhai, having fun?
你好，维克多 · 安娜，你好吗？
Hello, Victor Anna. How're you?
你好，阿南德·库玛吉，最近怎样？
Greetings, Anand Kumarji. How're you doing?
拉希尔，怎么了? 今天是投资的好日子
Rahil, what's up? It's a great day for investment.
今天就买下所有的股票
Buy all the shares today.
现在是保证利润的时候了
This is the time for a guaranteed profit.
不... 我向你保证
No... I guarantee you.
今天是投资的好日子，相信我
This is a good day to invest. Trust me.
太好了
That's great.
这是哈沙德的保证，别担心
It's Harshad's guarantee. Don't worry.
你想投资一大笔钱，对吧？
You wanted to invest a big amount, right?
来吧，多投一些！
Come on, spend some more!
这是收购股份的大好机会
It's a great opportunity to sweep up these shares.
最顺利的时候，这些股票会让你变得富有
This is the smoothest time. This share will make you rich.
如果你同意的话，这次我们可以给他沉重打击
If you agree, we can hit a sixer on this one.
好的，谢谢
Yes. Okay, thank you.
什么？
What?
当然，谢谢
Sure. Okay, thank you.
我很高兴我们今天早上卖掉了英卓尔
I'm glad we sold off Indrol this morning.
我们是不是应该平仓了？
Shall we square off the positions and book our profit?
- 你觉得呢?-不，让我们保持这个位置
- What say, Raju? - No. Let's hold the position.
还会继续跌
Indrol will drop further.
听着，过来
Listen, come here.
买入英卓尔的股票，告诉所有人
Buy Indrol. Tell everyone.
英卓尔! 英卓尔! 英卓尔！
Indrol! Indrol! Indrol!
我得去一下洗手间
I've to go to the washroom.
为了坚守阵地，我们遭受了严重的损失
In trying to hold our positions, we've incurred a serious loss.
我们都准备好了
We were all set.
突然，就在空头回补开始的时候..
-[phone rings] - Suddenly, just as short covering began...
股价涨起来了
...it started rising.
等一下，什么事？
One minute. Yes?
再见
Later.
谁在抬高股价？
Who's pushing it up?
在最后一刻，买单..
Manu Bhai, at the last moment, the buying orders...
拉朱! 别像个混蛋一样说话
Raju! Don't talk like an ass.
是谁在买入? LIC? UTI? 安巴尼？
Where are the buying orders coming from? LIC? UTI? Ambani?
- 谁买的?-我们不能肯定
- Who's buying it? - We can't say for sure.
但是那个哈尔沙德... 他心情很好，买了很多股票
But that Harshad... he was in good mood. He's buying a lot nowadays.
哈尔沙德? 谁? 那个该死的哈尔沙德・梅塔？
Harshad? Who? That f****r Harshad Mehta?
是的
Yes, Manu Bhai.
他给他的投资者60% 到70% 的回报
He's giving 60 to 70 percent returns to his investors.
- 谁在资助他?-不只是一个投资人
- And who's funding him? - It isn't just one source.
他们都是真正的投资者
They're all are genuine investors.
嘿，马赫什瓦里..
Hey, Maheshwari...
[电话铃声]
[phone ringing]
“稍等一会儿”
[Manu Manek] 'Hold on for a minute.'
在我们这个市场上，没有真正的投资者..
In this market of ours, there are no genuine investors...
每个人都是机会主义者
...Everyone is an opportunist.
你说的那个混蛋... 他叫什么名字？
And that a*****e you are talking about... what's his name?
- 哈尔沙德 · 梅塔-哈尔沙德 · 梅塔
- Harshad Mehta. -[Manu] 'Harshad Mehta.'
时机成熟时，我要确保他也倒下
When the time comes, we'll make sure he falls too.
大家好
[Newsreader] 'Greetings.'
印度财政部长维什瓦纳特•普拉塔普•辛格今天向议会提交了年度预算
' Finance Minister, Mr. Vishwanath Pratap Singh presented the annual budget in the parliament today.'
其中最精彩的部分是
'The highlights of which, are thus.'
[ Sucheta ]“在16个月的时间里，哈沙德买下了他能买到的一切... ... ”
[Sucheta] 'For 16 months, Harshad bought all he could...'
... 没有任何后备计划
'...without any backup plan.'
他对 Indrol、 Zuari Agro 和 SPIC 等公司进行了大量投资
'...he invested heavily in companies like Indrol, Zuari Agro and SPIC.
“公牛相信正在进行的自由化政策，并以此为先”
'The Bull set his pace trusting the on-going liberalisation policy.'
但是政府对长期财政政策的承诺..
'but the promises that the government had made on long-term fiscal policies...'
“ ... 已经被预算所遗忘”
'...had been forgotten in this budget.'
财政部长表示，在所有收入计算之后... ..
The finance minister said that after all revenue calculations...
... 明年的预算将赤字365亿卢比..
...next year's budget will be short by 3,650 crore rupees...
对于这个赤字还没有任何安排
...and for this deficit there is no arrangement yet.
恐惧总是压倒希望
[Sucheta] 'Fear always overpowers hope.'
“熊帮正是利用这种情绪来对抗牛市”
'And the bear gang was using this sentiment against the Bull.'
“牛削弱的那一刻，熊就强势起来了”
'The moment the Bull weakened, the Bears rose.'
这一次，马努攻击了哈尔沙德最喜欢的一只股票
'And this time Manu Mundra attacked one of Harshad's favourite stocks.'
SPIC
'SPIC.'
SPIC 是哈尔沙德的心脏所在
SPIC is where Harshad's heart is.
我们应该进一步拉低 SPIC
And we must pull SPIC down some more.
SPIC指数进一步下跌，哈尔萨德的指数就会下跌
The further SPIC falls, the lower Harshad drops.
这个哈尔沙德 · 梅塔是谁？
Who the f**k is this Harshad Mehta?
他是塔塔家的人吗? 他是安巴尼家的人吗? 他是谁？
Is he a Tata? Is he an Ambani? Who's he?
马赫什瓦里..
Maheshwari...
攻击股票只会... 啊啊啊！烫死我了
...targeting the stock will only... M**********r!
普拉蒙德? 你为什么用钢杯给我倒茶？
Pramod? Why did you get me tea in a steel cup?
我的天啊！
M**********r!
攻击股票只会动摇他，而不会击垮他
Targeting the stock will only shake him, not break him.
他可能会停顿一下，但他不会屈服
He might pause. But he won't bend.
如果有什么是应该攻击的... 不是股票，而是他的名声
If there's one thing we want to target... It's not the stock. It's his reputation.
马赫什瓦里，当你不能玷污别人的作品时，那就玷污他们的名声
Maheshwari, when you can't tarnish someone's work, tarnish their name.
他的名声越坏，人们就越不信任他
The worse his reputation, The lesser people will trust him.
没有信任，就不会有任何投资
And without trust, there won't be any investment.
如果没有投资，可以想象一下牛被阉割是什么样
Without investment, Consider the bull's balls cut forever.
就废了
It'll never rise again.
那么我们这样……
So let's do one thing.
我们在他的投资者中建立一种对哈尔萨德的观点
Let's create a perception about Harshad among his investors.
什么观点？
What perception?
哈尔沙德在 SPIC 损失了六七百万卢比
That Harshad has lost 60-70 lakhs in SPIC.
不... 不止这些
No... More than one crore.
这个数字一定要很大
The number must be huge.
到那时，交易员就会开始抛售他所持有的股票
That's when traders will start selling the stocks he holds.
一旦交易员开始抛售..
And once traders start selling...
就会变成自由落体！
It's a free fall. Yes!
这次牛将被献祭
The bull will be sacrificed this time.
- 怎么样，哈尔沙德兄弟?-欢迎
- What's up Harshad Bhai? - Welcome.
怎么了，吉涅什？
What's up, Jignesh Bhai?
报社记者来我家门口亲自传递消息！
Ahmedabad Samachar at my doorstep delivering news personally!
- 你怎么知道的?-对记者来说没什么是秘密的
- How did you know? - Nothing is secret for a reporter.
你什么都知道
You know everything about everything.
告诉我，标题是什么？
Tell me. What are the headlines?
马努的人正计划把你的名誉抛到九霄云外
Manu Bhai's people are planning to throw your reputation to the wind.
当然，他们会的
Of course, they will.
现在他把SPIC拉到这么低，很明显他会庆祝一下
Now that he's pulled SPIC so low, it's obvious he will celebrate a little.
随他去吧，我们马上就能扭转局势
Let him. We will turn the tide in no time.
明天，马努的人将进一步拉低 SPIC
Manu Bhai's people are going to further target SPIC tomorrow.
就这些吗，还是你有更多的消息？
Is that it or you have some more news?
市场上的内幕消息是，你将无法与交易所保持平衡
The inside news in the market is that you won't be able to square up with the exchange.
吉涅什兄弟，这不是内幕消息，这叫做谣言
Jignesh Bhai, that's not inside news. This is called a rumour.
我们在证交所有一千万卢比资金
We have a margin of one crore with BSE.
赔点钱对我们来说不算什么
We can easily cover the loss.
人们就这么容易受骗吗? 他们会盲目地相信马努吗？
Are people so gullible? That they will blindly believe Manu Bhai?
今天，马努的谎言被视为福音真理
Today, Manu Bhai's lies are taken as the gospel truth.
考虑一下，我要走了
Think about it. I'll be off.
- 留下喝点茶吧-下次吧
- Stay. Have some tea. - Next time.
我还有事
I have more news to deliver.
我不怕马努，他没那么强大
I'm not afraid of Manu Bhai. He's not that powerful.
当富人们在金房子里睡觉时..
While the rich sleep in chambers of gold...
穷人们在寒冷中熬夜
...the poor stay up all night in the cold.
你在说什么? 用我能听懂的语言说话
What are you saying? Speak in a language I understand.
兄弟
Look, Bhai.
我们不需要害怕马努
We don't need to fear Manu Bhai.
我们应该害怕那些相信马努的人
We need to be afraid of the people who believe in Manu Bhai.
那些担心一夜之间变穷的人
Those who are worried of becoming poor overnight.
马努无法摧毁我们
Manu Bhai cannot destroy us.
但是那些因为这个谣言而失眠的软弱的人，可以摧毁我们
But those weak people who lose their sleep over this rumour, can destroy us.
兄弟，我建议我们尽可能地撤出来，越快越好
Brother, I suggest we must pull back as much as we can, as soon as we can.
马努是冲着我们来的，他们拉低我们所持有的所有股票
We are the target. They'll try to break every position that we're holding.
布尚你说的太简单了
Bhushan, what you're saying is not that easy.
哈尔沙德，我们得想想办法
Harshad, we need to think of something.
他是要攻击我们的名声，对吗？
He is after our reputation, right?
那么只有一个办法可以拯救它
[Harshad] 'There's only one way of saving it.'
“我们要还清所有欠款”
'We have to clear all our dues.'
准备支票结清所有的欠款
'Let's prepare cheques to clear all payments.'
“旁边还有一封信，上面写着... ”
'And alongside, a letter that says...'
“忘掉违约，高摩提前14天清算债务”
'...Forget default, Growmore is clearing off its dues 14 days in advance.'
在市场开盘之前，让我们来见见玛雅大哥
And before the market opens, let's meet Mayya Bhai.
当证交所的执行董事宣布这一切都只是谣言... ..
'When the executive director of BSE announces that this is all just a rumour...'
... 每个人的耳朵都会竖起来
'...everyone's ears will perk up.'
“所有的付款支票都已经签好了”
'All the payment cheques are ready with signature.'
结算期为14天
The settlement period is of 14 days.
你为什么这么早付款？
Why are you clearing the payments so early?
因为这事关名誉
Because it's a matter of reputation.
我们知道..
We know...
通常人们会继续交易直到下一次结算
...that normally people carry forward the trade till the next settlement...
然后去找资金
...and then go looking for funds.
但是有些疯子在散布谣言..
But some people in BSE are spreading rumours...
说我们高摩没有资金
...that Growmore has no funds...
还说我们会拖欠款项
...and that we would default on our payments.
这就是为什么我要提前结清所有的欠款
That's why I'm clearing all the dues in advance.
这样一来，所有人都会明白，高摩并不缺乏资金
So that it becomes clear to all that Growmore is in no shortage of funds.
麻雅兄弟，请张贴告示..
Mayyaji, please put up a notice...
... 说”高摩一切都很好”
...saying "Everything is fine at Growmore".
因为如果那些散布谣言的人不闭嘴的话..
Because, if the people spreading these rumours don't shut up...
那么将会影响市场
...then more than Harshad Mehta, this will affect the market.
我不能张贴告示
I can't put up a notice.
不过别担心
But don't worry.
我会告诉董事会，高摩已经提前支付了所有的款项
I will tell the board that Growmore has paid all its dues in advance.
就市场而言..
And as far as the market goes...
别担心
Don't worry about that.
预算案通过后，市场动荡不安
The market is quite shaken up after the budget.
但我们不会让任何人如此轻易地操纵市场，不是吗？
And we won't let anyone manipulate the market so easily, will we?
不管是谁
Whoever that may be.
大哥，我马上给吉涅什打电话
Bhai, I will call Jignesh right away.
这条消息明天应该会登在每个财经专栏上
This news should be in every financial column tomorrow.
如果明天就出版，那就没有用了
It won't be of any use if it's published tomorrow.
这条消息必须在今天市场开盘前传达给人们
This news must reach people before the market opens today.
如果有必要的话，我们要大声宣布我们已经付款了
If required, we'll scream from the rooftops that we have made the payment.
会议怎么样，兄弟？
How was the meeting, brother?
‘ 布尚... ’
[Harshad] 'Bhushan...'
从瓦法达茶馆到三明治摊，从午餐之家到咖啡馆
'...from Wafadar Tea House to the sandwich stall, from the lunch home to Irani Cafe.'
像野火一样传播这个消息..
Spread this news like wildfire...
梅塔已经付了钱
...that Mehta has made the payment.
不要拿任何人的钱
Don't take money from anyone.
告诉大家今天哈尔沙德在餐厅请所有人喝茶
Tell everyone that tea is on Harshad Mehta today.
他是证交所的阿米塔布·巴强（宝莱坞明星）
He's the Bachchan of BSE.
谁不认识他？
Who doesn't know him?
哈尔沙德就代表着证交所，看看这个
BSE means Harshad Mehta. Look at that.
恭喜哈沙德 · 梅塔，茶算在哈尔沙德 · 巴伊身上
'CONGRATULATIONS TO HARSHAD MEHTA. TEA IS ON HARSHAD BHAI.'
这个消息应该传到疯牛病的每一个角落
[Harshad] 'This news should reach every nook and cranny of BSE...'
“ ... ... 哈尔沙德 · 梅塔不只是说说而已，他是在行动”
'...that Harshad Mehta doesn't just talk. He acts.'
“大力宣传这一信息，以至于没有人会怀疑梅塔兄弟的诚实”
'Push the message so hard that nobody ever doubts the honesty of the Mehta Brothers.'
今天哈尔沙德请客
Tea is on Harshad Bhai today.
免费? 什么情况？
Free? What's the occasion?
大家都说哈沙德 · 巴伊破产了
Everyone was saying that Harshad Bhai is bankrupt.
但是他已经提前支付了所有人的款项
But he's cleared everyone's payments in advance.
- 提前?-是的
- In advance? - Yes.
让交易所的每一个经纪人都知道，现在是我们的时代了
[Harshad] 'Let every jobber and broker of BSE know that it's our time now.'
“任何人都不应该心存疑虑”
'There should be no doubt in anyone's mind.'
在梅塔的统治下，市场将陷入疯狂
'In Mehta's reign, the market will go insane.'
如果哈尔沙德愿意的话，他可以等到协议期结束
Harshad could have waited out the settlement period, if he wanted.
但他没有
But he didn't.
为了自己的名誉，他个人蒙受了巨大的损失
He incurred such a huge personal loss for the sake of his reputation.
每个人都在说，‘在梅塔的统治下，市场将变得疯狂’
Everyone is saying, 'In Mehta's reign, the market will go insane.'
疯狂？
Insane?
别像个傻瓜一样说话
Don't talk like a fool.
这种疯狂不会持续很久的
This insanity won't last long.
那个该死的家伙最后会一贫如洗
The f****r will end up naked.
混蛋
M**********r.
他能自己掏多久的腰包？
How long will he pay from his own pocket?
让马努见鬼去吧! 该死的眼镜蛇！
To hell with Manu! Bloody Cobra!
原来你是只猫鼬
You turned out to be a mongoose.
猫鼬的意思是... 眼镜蛇杀手
Mongoose means... Cobra killer.
你就是眼镜蛇杀手，就连莫塔海今天也该感谢他了
You are the Cobra killer. Even MotaBhai must be thanking him today.
穷人现在可以得到一些喘息的机会，反而那个有钱人今晚会失眠
The poor can now get some respite. That rich m**********r won't sleep tonight.